https://jesscs.github.io/

SUMMARY

Research scientist specialized in human-computer interaction (HCI) and health informatics, with extensive experience in conducting formative studies to identify needs and opportunities; iterative design and development of novel methods and tools to support those needs; and evaluations to examine usage and develop design implications for future tools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2020 - Present **Research Scientist, Evidation Health**

Collaboratively designs, conducts, and analyzes novel quantitative and mixed-methods studies to answer internal and client questions around health-related perspectives, behaviors, and experiences, tailoring study design to project goals (e.g., market research, patient-centered design, publication).

2014 - 2020 Research Assistant, University of Washington

Investigated supporting people and their health providers in collecting, analyzing, and interpreting patient-generated data to meet personalized health goals in multiple health contexts.

Conducted surveys and interviews to characterize needs and opportunities in health contexts.

Collaborated with health providers in the design and evaluation of novel prototype health apps, including mobile apps and interactive, exploratory visualizations.

Research resulted in related grants from the NSF (\$500k) and the NIH (\$1.5M).

More detailed descriptions available on my personal website.

Research Intern, Microsoft Research Summer 2017

Conducted a feasibility study to investigate how a mobile app can support behavioral therapy.

Designed and analyzed surveys to: 1) characterize significant positive changes in anxiety, depression, and coping skill use; 2) develop a theoretical model to describe how the app supported these improvements; and 3) distill design implications for future tools.

Identified opportunities for machine learning techniques to provide personalized and context-aware suggestions to help people identify feasible and useful positive coping skills.

2013 - 2014 **Project Manager, Harvey Mudd Clinic**

Led development of a web app to provide personalized vacation recommendations for Expedia.

2013 Undergraduate Research Assistant, Carnegie Mellon HCII

Investigated augmentations of a chronic illness forum to help people find credible information.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2020 University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Ph.D., Computer Science & Engineering. GPA: 3.9

M.S. earned 12/2016

Dissertation: Goal-Directed Self-Tracking in the Management of Chronic Health Conditions

Advisors: James Fogarty, Sean Munson

2010 - 2014 Pomona College, Claremont, CA

B.A., Computer Science. GPA: 3.9

Skills

Semi-structured interviews, surveys, field studies, observation, contextual inquiry, RITE. User Research

Data Analysis Qualitative data analysis (e.g., coding, thematic analysis, affinity diagraming);

Quantitative data analysis (e.g., R, Python, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn).

Prototyping Prototypes, mobile and web app development (e.g., Angular, Ionic, D3.js).

Leadership Project management; communication (e.g., scientific and technical writing, presentations);

diversity and inclusion advocacy.

AWARDS & HONORS

2017, 2018 Best Paper Award (CHI 2017) and Honorable Mentions (CHI 2017, DIS 2018)

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship Program Awardee
Marilyn Fries Endowed Regental Fellowship Recipient

2014 ARCS Foundation Fellow

2014 Harvey Mudd Computer Science Clinic Team Award Winner

2013 DREU-CRAW Participant

2013 Grace Hopper Scholarship Recipient

2010 - 2013 Pomona College Scholar

TEACHING, SERVICE, AND LEADERSHIP

Reviewer CHI 2017-2021; CSCW 2018-2019; DIS 2018-2019; IMWUT 2019.

Teaching Assistant Designed and graded assignments, critiqued projects, and advised UW graduate students

in CSE 510: Advanced Topics in HCI (Winter 2018, Fall 2018).

HCI Seminar Lead Led improvements to the Computer Science department's weekly HCI seminar and

organized quarterly themes, presentations, and feedback (January 2017—June 2018).

Coordinated one-on-ones with faculty and current graduate students and organized social activity (Winter 2018); reviewed graduate student applications (Fall 2016).
Orientation Leader
Organized orientation for the new Computer Science graduate students (Fall 2016).
Writing Fellow
Worked with Pomona students to improve their writing (Fall 2011—Spring 2014).

Senior Science Fellow for the 2013/2014 academic year.

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

Full publication lists available on my personal website and my Google Scholar Page.

J Schroeder, J Suh, C Wilks, M Czerwinski, SA Munson, J Fogarty, T Althoff. <u>Data-Driven Implications for</u> Translating Evidence-Based Psychotherapies into Technology-Delivered Interventions. *PervasiveHealth* 2020.

J Schroeder, R Karkar, N Murinova, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Examining Opportunities for Goal-Directed Self-Tracking to Support Chronic Condition Management</u>. *UbiComp* 2020.

J Schroeder, J Fogarty, S Munson. <u>Personalizing Health Technologies to Support Patient and Provider Goals</u>. CSCW 2019 Workshop on Identifying Challenges and Opportunities in Human–AI Collaboration in Healthcare.

CF Chung, Q Wang, **J Schroeder**, A Cole, J Zia, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Identifying and Planning for Individualized Change</u>: <u>Patient-Provider Collaboration Using Lightweight Food Diaries in Healthy Eating</u> and Irritable Bowel Syndrome. *UbiComp* 2019.

J Schroeder, R Karkar, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson, M Kay. <u>A Patient-Centered Proposal for Bayesian</u> Analysis of Self-Experiments for Health. *JHIR* 2018.

J Schroeder, CF Chung, DA Epstein, R Karkar, A Parsons, N Murinova, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Examining Self-Tracking by People with Migraine: Goals, Needs, and Opportunities in a Chronic Health Condition.</u> *DIS 2018.* Best Paper Honorable Mention.

J Schroeder, C Wilks, K Rowan, A Toledo, A Paradiso, M Czerwinski, G Mark, MM Linehan. <u>Pocket Skills:</u> A Conversational Mobile Web App To Support Dialectical Behavioral Therapy. *CHI 2018*.

R Karkar, **J Schroeder**, D Epstein, L Pina, J Scofield, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson, R Vilardaga, J Zia. <u>TummyTrials</u>: A Feasibility Study of Using Self-Experimentation to Detect Individualized Food Triggers. *CHI 2017*. Best Paper Honorable Mention.

CF Chung, E Agapie, **J Schroeder**, S Mishra, J Fogarty, S Munson. When Personal Tracking Becomes Social: Examining the Use of Instagram for Healthy Eating. *CHI* 2017.

D Epstein, N Lee, J Kang, E Agapie, **J Schroeder**, L Pina, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson. <u>Examining</u> Menstrual Tracking to Inform the Design of Personal Informatics Tools. *CHI 2017*. Best Paper Awardee.

J Schroeder, J Hoffswell, CF Chung, J Fogarty, S Munson, J Zia. <u>Supporting Patient-Provider Collaboration to Identify Individual Triggers using Food and Symptom Journals</u>. *CSCW 2017*.